Turbulent Skies is a action, thriller, tv movie film directed by Fred Olen Ray.
When a new airplane that's equipped with a new computer that can fly
the plane on its own, is about to have its first flight.
But the son of the owner decides to upload more software, he doesn't
bother to check if there are any viruses with it.
And he also invites some potential investors to try it.
So the plane appears to be working well but suddenly it
veers off course and it can't be shut down.
When the military learns of this and fears what if something happens if it's over a
populated area; decides to shoot it down along with everyone on board.
The man who built the computer whose wife is among the passengers thinks if he can get on
board he might be able to shut it down and regain control of the plane.
So the military using a new plane gets him on board.
But what he didn't know is that both pilots are
incapacitated so there's no one who can fly the plane.
Tom, played by Casper Van Dien.
Samantha, played by Nicole Eggert.
Charles, played by Patrick Muldoon.
First Officer Peterson, played by Ted Monte.
Cooper, played by Mark Enticknap.
General's Second Aide, played by Gerald Webb.
Castle in the Sky, also known as Laputa: Castle in the Sky, is a 1986 Japanese
animated fantasy adventure film written and directed by Hayao Miyazaki.
It was produced by Isao Takahata, animated by
Studio Ghibli, and distributed by Toei.
The film stars the voices of Mayumi Tanaka, Keiko
Yokozawa, Kotoe Hatsui, and Minori Terada.
In the film, orphans Sheeta and Pazu are pursued by government
agent Muska, the army, and a group of pirates.
They seek Sheeta's crystal necklace, the key to accessing Laputa, a
legendary flying castle hosting advanced technology.
Castle in the Sky was the first film to be animated by Studio Ghibli.
Its production team included many of Miyazaki's longtime collaborators, who would
continue to work with the studio for the following three decades.
The film was partly inspired by Miyazaki's trips to Wales, where he
witnessed the aftermath of the 1984–1985 coal miners' strike.
The island of Laputa is used to highlight the theme of environmentalism, exploring the relationships
between humanity, nature, and technology, a reflection of Miyazaki's ecological philosophy.
The young protagonists also provide a unique perspective on the narrative, as a result of
Miyazaki's desire to portray "the honesty and goodness of children in [his] work".
Many aspects of the film's retrofuturistic style – the flying machines in particular – are influenced by
nineteenth-century approaches, which has earned the film a reputation in the modern steampunk genre.
The film was released in Japanese theaters on August 2, 1986.
It underperformed expectations at the box office, but later achieved commercial
success through rereleases, earning over US$157 million as of 2021.
An English dub commissioned by Tokuma Shoten was distributed in North America by Streamline Pictures, and
another dub was produced by Disney in 1998, released internationally by Buena Vista in 2003.
The film's score was composed by Joe Hisaishi, who would become a close collaborator of
Miyazaki's; Hisaishi also composed a reworked soundtrack for the 2003 English dub.
The film was generally acclaimed by critics, though the
English dubs received mixed reviews.
It was well received by audiences, being voted as one of the greatest animated films
in polls conducted by the Agency for Cultural Affairs and Oricon.
The film also received several notable accolades, including the Ōfuji Noburō Award
at the Mainichi Film Awards and the Anime Grand Prix from Animage.
Castle in the Sky has since earned "cult status", and has influenced
several notable artists working in multiple media.
The tone is intense.